<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on DBGroup</title>
    <link>https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on DBGroup</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; DB Group, 2020 </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 14:45:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>CV Direction</title>
      <link>https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/project_model_zengd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 14:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/project_model_zengd/</guid>
      <description>Reserach Project I - 2D Face recognition and 3D Face Modeling Face recognition has been one of the most challenging and active research topics in computer vision and pattern recognition for several decades. Meanwhile, as one of the most commonly used biometric recognition technique, it is widely applied in the domains of national security, social security, finance, etc. In recent years, face recognition techniques under uncontrolled environment have achieved remarkable progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization Direction</title>
      <link>https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/project_model_vis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 14:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/project_model_vis/</guid>
      <description>Efficient and effective data visualization Spatial-temporal visualization techniques have been applied in various real-world applications and assist the data exploration by leveraging the sharp perception of human analysts. However, large data visualization is challenging. 1) The long data to visualization latency (query time, computing time and rendering time) always break the continuity of the human involved data exploration loop; 2) visual clutter caused by a large amount of data hinders the ability of the human to discover the insight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>大规模相似性检索</title>
      <link>https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/large-scale-similarity-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 14:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://danielmao1.github.io/zh/project/large-scale-similarity-search/</guid>
      <description>相似性检索是指对于一个给定的查询，在包含众多物品的数据集中，找出与其最相似物品的任务。相似性检索是数据处理中最常见的操作之一，有着包括推荐、图片检索、文件检索和实体识别在内的众多应用。由于其广泛的应用，包括Google, Microsoft 和Facebook在内的众多公司都在开展相似性检索研究。但高效相似性检索面临着诸多挑战——数据集的规模很大，可以包含上亿个高维向量；检索对处理时延和结果质量的要求都很高，例如在10ms内召回率达到0.9. 在这个课题下，我们将从以下方面开展研究：
 设计针对不同相似性度量的检索算法，包括欧氏距离，内积，编辑距离等； 利用先进硬件进行相似性检索，例如GPU, SSD 和NVM； 横跨多台服务器的分布式相似性检索； 用机器学习技术改善相似性检索算法。  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
